<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<Vulnerability id="cmty-http-ricoh-no-password" published="2007-11-28" added="2007-11-28" modified="2016-10-25" version="1.0">
  <name>Un-authenticated Ricoh document server access</name>
  <severity>3</severity>
  <pci severity="1"/>
  <Tags>
     <tag>Web</tag>
  </Tags>
  <cvss>(AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:P/I:N/A:N)</cvss>
  <AlternateIds>
    <id name="URL">http://support.ricoh.com/bb_v1oi/pub_e/oi_view/0001036/0001036377/view/copy/unv/0167.htm></id>  
  </AlternateIds>
  <Description>
     <p>Ricoh Document servers may be missconfigured to allow for un-authenticated access to documents stored on the devices.
     </p>
  </Description>
  <Solutions>
    <Solution id="cmty-http-ricoh-no-password" time="5m">
      <summary>Configure a password to prevent un-authenticated access to documents stored on the system.</summary>
      <workaround>
          <p>To prevent unauthorized printing, you can set a password for any stored document. A protected document can only be accessed if its password is entered. If a password is set for the documents, the key icon appears next to the documents.
              1.  Press the [Document Server] key.
              2. Press [Scan Original].
              3. Enter a user name, file name, and password, if necessary.
              
              When not changing a file name, the name will be automatically set.
              
              4. Set the original.
              5. Specify the original scanning conditions.
              6. Press the [Start] key.
              
              The original is scanned. The document is saved in the Document Server.
              
              Note
  
              Enter the password in the range of four and eight digits.
              
              To stop scanning, press the [Clear/Stop] key. To restart a paused scanning job, press [Continue] in the confirmation display. To delete saved images and cancel the job, press [Stop]. The original placed in the ADF will be ejected.<br/>
              
              If a password is set, the key icon appears on the left side of the file name.
              
              After scanning, a list of stored documents will be displayed. If the list does not appear, press [Finish Scanning].
              
              Data stored in the Document Server is set to be deleted after three days (72 hours) by the factory default. You can specify the period after which the stored data is deleted automatically under Auto Delete File in Document Server in User Tools. See "System Settings", Network and System Settings Guide.
              
              If you do not want stored documents to be automatically deleted, select [Off] in Auto Delete File in Document Server before storing a document. If you select [On] later, data stored after will be automatically deleted.
              
              When storing another document in the Document Server after storing a document from the copy feature, be sure that its copy is completed.
              
              Depending on the security setting, [Access Privileges] may appear instead of [User Name]. For details about specifying [Access Privileges], consult the administrator.
              
              For details about how to enter text, see "Entering Text", About This Machine.</p>
    </workaround>
    </Solution>
  </Solutions>
</Vulnerability>
